A life of love, courage & fellowship.
Tolkien is a war, drama, romance film directed by Dome Karukoski.
England, early 20th century.
The future writer and philologist John Ronald Reuel Tolkien (1892-1973) and three of his schoolmates create a strong bond between them as they share the same
passion for literature and art, a true fellowship that strengthens as they grow up, but the outbreak of World War I threatens to shatter it.
J.R.R. Tolkien, played by Nicholas Hoult.
Edith Bratt, played by Lily Collins.
Father Francis Morgan, played by Colm Meaney.
Professor Joseph Wright, played by Derek Jacobi.
Young J.R.R. Tolkien, played by Harry Gilby.
Young Edith Bratt, played by Mimi Keene.
Tolkien is a 2019 biographical drama film directed by Dome Karukoski
and written by David Gleeson and Stephen Beresford.
It is about the early life of English professor and philologist J.
Tolkien, author of The Hobbit (1937), The Lord of the Rings (1954–55), and
The Silmarillion (1977) as well as notable academic works.
The film stars Nicholas Hoult, Lily Collins, Colm Meaney, and Derek Jacobi.
Tolkien was released in the United Kingdom on 3 May 2019, and in the United States on 10 May 2019, by Fox Searchlight
Pictures, and was the first feature film released after the acquisition of 21st Century Fox by Disney.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $9
million worldwide on a $20 million budget.
The film explores themes of world war i, male friendship,
biography, based on true story, coming of age.
The tone is emotional.